Finding aid to Buildings records CA.MS.00104
Smith College Archives
Buildings records
1866- 2008
Smith College Archives
Smith College.
CA.MS.00104
52.042 linear feet (133 containers)
The Buildings records focus on the College's buildings, both extant and demolished. This collection interprets the term "building" loosely, and includes information not only about the buildings themselves, but also about what occurred / occurs in the buildings, especially where student residences are concerned. Much of Smith College student life is and has long been centered in the residential houses, and so a buildings file may contain annual group photographs of house residents, student rosters, house government material, and information on house traditions, in addition to the architectural information, ownership history, and photographs of the building itself.
Biographical / Historical
Smith College was incorporated in 1871 and opened with fourteen enrolled students in 1875. Therefore, most of the extant buildings were erected after 1875, though there are quite a few that date from the earlier part of the 19th century and even some from the 18th. The campus is and always has been a mixture of constructed and acquired buildings: Smith' s first three buildings were Dewey House-former home of Northampton judge Charles Augustus Dewey, College Hall-built by the trustees as the first academic and administrative building, and Gateway House-built by the trustees as a home for Smith's first president, L. Clark Seelye (1875-1910). Dewey was home to the very first Smith students and today houses faculty offices and meeting rooms. The present-day campus as a whole serves as an "architectural garden," with styles ranging from Colonial to Greek Revival and Victorian Gothic to neo-Georgian, with a dose of "modern" styles added more recently.
Scope and Contents
The Buildings records are part of the larger Buildings and Grounds collection and focus on the College's buildings, both extant and demolished. The vast majority of information in the collection falls between 1875 and the present, though there are a few scattered items from before 1875. The College Archives staff is continually adding new information to the files. This collection interprets the term "building" loosely, and includes information not only about the buildings themselves, but also about what occurred / occurs in the buildings, especially where student residences are concerned. Much of Smith College student life is and long has been centered in the residential houses, and so a buildings file may contain annual group photographs of house residents, student rosters, house government material, and information on house traditions, in addition to the architectural information, ownership history, and photographs of the building itself. The collection also interprets "Smith building" loosely, containing limited information on a number of privately-owned, off-campus boarding-houses.
Related Material
Those with more than a cursory interest in the Buildings of Smith College would do well to consult one or more of the following sources outside the 22. Buildings collection:
Card Catalog: Entries may contain any or all of the following information about a building:
Construction / acquisition date
Architect
Information on who the building was named for
Information on how the building has been used at various times
Cross-references to specific locations outside of 22. Buildings
List of "house mothers" (current and former student residences)
Small identifying photograph of the building
Other Smith College Archives Collections
00. Northampton and Local History may be helpful in understanding the early growth and expansion of the College within the context of the local community.
10. Postcard Collection features images of nearly all Smith buildings. This collection is digitized and available online at http://clio.fivecolleges.edu/smith/postcards/.
20. Buildings and Grounds-General includes maps of campus, some architectural information not contained in 22., and other general information about the College's physical plant. There is no finding aid yet available for this collection.
24. Buildings and Grounds-Grounds is the counterpart to 22. Buildings. It contains information on the Botanic Gardens, Paradise Pond, the old Allen Field, and numerous other college properties. There is no finding aid yet available for this collection.
32. Presidential Papers of Laurenus Clark Seelye (1875-1910), Marion LeRoy Burton (1910-1917), William Allan Neilson (1917-1939), Herbert John Davis (1940-1949), Benjamin Fletcher Wright (1949-1959), Thomas Corwin Mendenhall (1959-1975), Jill Ker Conway (1975-1985), and Mary Maples Dunn (1985-1995). All of these collections have finding aids.
Smith College Publications
President's Reports of Smith presidents named above.
Smith Alumnae Quarterly, Smith College Weekly, SCAN, The Sophian. These publications are helpful when there is a controversy surrounding a building, or when a building is to be built or demolished. The December 15, 1944 special one-page edition of SCAN reporting on the fire in Dickinson House is a particularly good example. Access these publications through the card catalog, or simply look up the appropriate dates in the Reading Room copies.
Sources Outside the Smith College Archives
Smith College Physical Plant Department holds most of the college's oversized architectural plans. Researchers are welcome to view these plans, but an appointment must be scheduled ahead-of-time with Physical Plant, either directly or through the Archives. Plans are viewed at the Physical Plant facility on West Street.
http://www.smith.edu/construction/ is a website, current as of March 2002, containing information on current Smith College building projects.
Campus Tours are conducted for students interested in attending Smith College, so the focus is not necessarily on the actual buildings, but a tour would enable a non-Smith researcher to see extant buildings "live" with a guide. Call the Admissions Office for tour schedules, or take a "virtual tour" at http://www.smith.edu/tour/ (web address current as of March 2002).
Conditions Governing Access
All but two (2) boxes are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The material in the Buildings Collection comes to the Archives from a wide variety of sources over an extended period of time.
Bibliography
The Early History of Smith College 1871-1910. L. Clark Seelye. Houghton Mifflin: Boston, MA, 1923. This, the House We Live In: The Smith College Campus from 1871 to 1982. Eleanor Terry Lincoln and John Abel Pinto. Smith College: Northampton, MA, 1983. Note: This, the House We Live In is the most directly useful in this context, providing short histories of each building in the order of their construction or acquisition by the College and an alphabetical index. It also contains a quick but thorough narrative history of Smith College's expansion from the original Dewey and Lyman Homesteads to its present-day landholdings, and a discussion of the overall architectural history of the College. The book also separately lists the construction date and architect of each building if that information is known.
Smith College--Buildings.; Smith College--History--Sources.; Smith College--Pictorial works.; Smith College--Students.
- Ada Dormitory (Box 189, Folder 0.5)
- Ahwaga Avenue, 1909 (Box 189, Folder 1)
  General
  [see also 00. Northampton-Streets]
- Ainsworth Gym (Box 189)
  [see Gymnasium-Ainsworth]
- Albright House
  - -General, 1933-; undated (Box 189, Folder 2)
  - -Artifacts
    [see Appendix E]
  - -Bathroom Stall Graffiti, Spring 1977 (Box 189, Folder 3)
  - -Photographs-Exterior, 1900-; undated (Box 189, Folder 4)
  - -Photographs-Interior, 1900-; undated (Box 189, Folder 5)
  - -Photographs-Groups, 1909-; undated (Box 189, Folder 6)
  - -Scrapbook (in honor of housemother Lois B. Bateson), 1958-1968
    [see Oversize Box 1 (Appendix H)]
  - -Scrapbook, 1962-1969
    [see Oversize Box 2 (Appendix H)]
- Miss Allen's Tea Room and Gift Shop
  [see Elm Street, # 150]
- Alumnae Gymnasium
  [see Gymnasium-Alumnae]
- Alumnae House (8 Bedford Terrace location), 1914-1924; undated (Box 189.1, Folder 1)
  - -Photographs-Exterior, 1913-1938 (Box 189.1, Folder 2)
  - -Photographs-Interior, 1913-1938 (Box 189.1, Folder 3)
- Alumnae House (Elm Street location)
  - -General, 1939-; undated (Box 189.1, Folder 4)
  - -Anniversaries, 1948; 1988 (Box 189.1, Folder 5)
  - -Architectural Plans
    [see Flat File Drawer 6 (Appendix H)]
  - -Dedication, 1938 (Box 189.1, Folder 6)
  - -Deed of Gift, 1938 (Box 189.1, Folder 7)
  - -Exhibits, 1939-1942 (Box 189.1, Folder 8)
  - -Funding, 1931-1938 (Box 189.1, Folder 9)
  - -Groundbreaking, 1937 (Box 189.1, Folder 10)
  - -Laying of Cornerstone, 1937 (Box 189.1, Folder 11)
  - -Plaques, undated (Box 189.1, Folder 12)
  - -Photographs
    - -Exterior, 1938-; undated (Box 189.1, Folder 13)
    - -Interior, 1940-; undated (Box 189.1, Folder 14)
    - -Interior-Special Features, 1939-1994 (Box 189.1, Folder 15)
    - -Cornerstone, 1937; 1980 (Box 189.1, Folder 16)
    - -Dedication, 1938 (Box 189.1, Folder 17)
    - -Groundbreaking and Construction, 1937 (Box 189.1, Folder 18)
  - -Sketches and Drawings (Architectural), 1936 (Box 189.1, Folder 19)
- The Anchorage (103 South Street), undated (Box 189.1, Folder 20)
- Arnold Avenue
  - -#12, 1899-1924 (Box 189.1, Folder 21)
  - -#16 (Even Inn) (Box 189.1, Folder 22)
    - -General, 1912 (Box 189.1)
    - -Histories, 1913-1915 (Box 189.1, Folder 23)
    - -Scrapbooks (2) from Class of 1910
      [see Oversize Box 3 (Appendix H)]
- Baker Properties, undated (Box 189.2, Folder 1)
- Baldwin House
  - -General, 1956-; undated (Box 189.2, Folder 2)
  - -Calendar, 1910 (Box 189.2, Folder 3)
  - -Photographs-Exterior, 1908-; undated (Box 189.2, Folder 4)
  - -Photographs-Interior, 1981 (Box 189.2, Folder 5)
  - -Photographs-Groups, 1910-1995 (Box 189.2, Folder 6)
- Bedford Terrace
  - -Map, undated (Box 189.2, Folder 7)
  - -# 6 (The Rosemont), 1907; 1975 (Box 189.2, Folder 8)
  - -# 6 (The Rosemont)-Photographs, 1916-1975; undated (Box 189.2, Folder 9)
  - -# 8, 1904-1997 (Box 189.2, Folder 10)
    [see also Alumnae House (8 Bedford Terrace location) and see also Dawes House and see also German House]
  - -# 12, 1901; 1974 (Box 189.2, Folder 11)
  - -# 26, 1917-1949; undated (Box 189.2, Folder 12)
  - -# 36
    [see Pomeroy House]
- Belmont Avenue
  - -# 8, 1927-1929 (Box 190, Folder 1)
  - -# 9, 1906 (Box 190, Folder 1a)
  - -# 9-Photographs, 1910-1930 (Box 190, Folder 2)
  - -# 12, 1909-1918; undated (Box 190, Folder 3)
  - -# 13, 1919-1930 (Box 190, Folder 4)
  - -# 16
    [see White Lodge]
  - -# 17, 1901; 1923 (Box 190, Folder 5)
  - -# 20, 1902-1924 (Box 190, Folder 6)
  - -# 21, 1910-1925 (Box 190, Folder 7)
  - -# 21-Photograph Album, 1899-1914
  - -# 22, 1927; undated (Box 190, Folder 8)
  - -# 29, undated (Box 190, Folder 9)
  - -#30, 1930-1957 (Box 190, Folder 10)
  - -#54, 1913-1919 (Box 190, Folder 11)
- Boat and Crew Houses
  [see also 24. Paradise Pond]
  - -Boat House, 1911- (Box 190, Folder 12)
  - -Crew House, 1975- (Box 190, Folder 13)
  - -Crew House-Architectural Plans
  - -Photographs-Boat House, 1900 (Box 190, Folder 14)
  - -Photographs-Boat House, 1910- (Box 190, Folder 15)
  - -Photographs-Crew House, 1985-; undated (Box 190, Folder 16)
  - -Photographs-Both, 1910- (Box 190, Folder 17)
  - -Photographs-Both (Box 190)
    [see also Oversize Box 9 (Appendix H)]
- Bookstore (Green Street), 1980- (Box 190, Folder 18)
- Brass Knocker
  [see Elizabeth Drew House]
- Burnham House
  [see Mary Ellen Chase House]
- Burton Hall
  [see also Science Center-Clark Science Center]
  - -General, 1905-; undated (Box 190, Folder 19)
  - -Architectural Plans
    [see Burton Hall-Sketches and Drawings and Flat File Drawer 6 (Appendix H)]
  - -Photographs-Exterior, 1914-; undated (Box 190, Folder 20)
  - -Photographs-Interior, 1915-; undated (Box 190, Folder 21)
  - -Sketches and Drawings (Architectural), undated (Box 190, Folder 22)
- Cable House (Clark House Annex), 1888-1908 (Box 191, Folder 1)
- Campus Center, 1996- (Box 191, Folder 2)
- Campus School, 1973 (Box 191, Folder 3)
  [see also Gill Hall]
- Capen Gymnasium
  [see Davis Student Center]
- Capen House
  - -General, 1921-; undated (Box 191, Folder 4)
  - -History, 1922-1952 (Box 191, Folder 5)
  - -House President's Notebook, 1957-1978 (Box 191, Folder 6)
  - -Watchbook, 1967 (Box 191, Folder 7)
  - -Miscellaneous, undated (Box 191, Folder 7a)
  - -Photographs
    - -Exterior, 1900- (Box 191, Folder 8)
    - -Interior, 1981-; undated (Box 191, Folder 9)
    - -Groups, 1887-1954; undated (Box 191, Folder 10)
    - -Groups (Album), 1956 (Box 191, Folder 11)
    - -Groups (Album), 1957 (Box 191, Folder 12)
    - -Groups (Album), 1958 (Box 192, Folder 1)
    - -Groups (Album), 1959 (Box 192, Folder 2)
    - -Groups (Album), 1960 (Box 192, Folder 1)
    - -Groups, 1961 (Box 192, Folder 2)
    - -Groups (Album), 1962 (Box 192, Folder 3)
    - -Groups, 1965-1966 (Box 192, Folder 4)
    - -Groups, 1967 (Box 192, Folder 5)
    - -Groups, 1968 (Box 192, Folder 6)
    - -Groups (Box 192)
      [see also Oversize Box 10 (Appendix H)]
- Capen House Annex
  [see 20. Maps for location (no file)]
- Career Development Office (CDO)
- Center for the Performing Arts
  [see Individual Document Box 7]
- Center Street Avenue # 19
  [see Sheldon House]
- Chapel
  [see Individual Document Boxes 8-12]
- Chapin House
  [see Individual Document Box 15]
- Chase House
- Chiller Plant, 1990-1991 (Box 192, Folder 7)
- Clark House
  - -General, 1908-1972 (Box 192, Folder 8)
  - -Photographs-Exterior, 1892-1982 (Box 192, Folder 9)
  - -Photographs-Groups, 1900-1982 (Box 192, Folder 10)
- Clark House Annex
  [see Cable House]
- College Hall
  [see Individual Document Boxes 16-19]
- College Lane
  - -# 7, undated (Box 192, Folder 11)
  - -# 8, undated (Box 192, Folder 12)
  - -# 51
    [see Faculty Clubhouse]
- Comstock House
  [see also Quadrangle and see also Quadrangle-Mandelle Quad and see also Wilder House]
  - -General, 1930-; undated (Box 192, Folder 13)
  - -Artifacts
  - -Library, 1940 (Box 192, Folder 14)
  - -Photographs-Exterior, 1956-; undated (Box 192, Folder 15)
  - -Photographs-Interior, 1930 (Box 192, Folder 16)
  - -Photographs-Groups, 1936- (Box 192, Folder 17)
- Center for the Performing Arts (Mendenhall Center)
  - -General, 1962- (Box 192.1, Folder 1)
  - -Bells, 1968-1997 (Box 192.1, Folder 2)
  - Bell Tower: Change Ringers Album (Box 192.2)
  - -Construction-Architectural Drawings, 1965 (Box 193, Folder 3)
    [see also Flat File Drawer 6 (Appendix H)]
  - -Construction-Plans, 1966 (Box 193, Folder 4)
  - -Construction-Renovations, 1998-2001 (Box 193, Folder 5)
  - -Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 193, Folder 6)
  - -Historic Clothing Collection, 1985 (Box 193, Folder 7)
  - -Photographs
    - -Exterior, 1968-; undated (Box 193, Folder 8)
    - -Interior, undated (Box 193, Folder 9)
    - -Bells, 1968 (Box 193, Folder 10)
    - -Construction, 1967 (Box 193, Folder 11)
    - -Landscaping, 1967-1978; undated (Box 193, Folder 12)
  - -Sketches and Drawings
- Chapel-College Hall Chapel
  - -General, 1875-1890 (Box 193.1, Folder 1)
  - -Photographs, 1875-1890 (Box 193.1, Folder 2)
  - -Photographs, 1890-1900 (Box 193.1, Folder 3)
  - -Photographs, 1900-1910 (Box 193.1, Folder 4)
- Chapel-John M. Greene Hall, 1910-37; 1954-55 (Box 193.1, Folder 5)
- Chapel-John M. Greene Hall-Photographs, 1910-1937 (Box 193.1, Folder 6)
- Chapel-Neilson Library (Little Chapel)
  - -General, 1936-1962 (Box 193.1, Folder 7)
  - -Bookplate
    [see Libraries-Bookplates-Branch and Specialty Libraries]
  - -Furnishings and Gifts, 1937-1956; undated (Box 193.1, Folder 8)
  - -Hymnal, 1938 (Box 193.1, Folder 9)
  - -Photographs, 1937-1955 (Box 193.1, Folder 10)
- Chapel-Proposed Chapel, 1933 (Box 193.1, Folder 11)
- Chapel-Helen Hills Hills Chapel
  - -General, 1955-; undated (Box 194, Folder 1)
  - -25th Anniversary (September 16, 1979)
    - -General, 1979 (Box 194, Folder 2)
    - -General Plans and Proposals, 1978-1979 (Box 194, Folder 3)
    - -Fall Events, 1979 (Box 194, Folder 4)
    - -Haughton, Rosemary, 1975-1979 (Box 194, Folder 5)
    - -Parents' Weekend (April 20, 1980) (Box 194, Folder 6)
    - -Rally Day, FEB 1980 (Box 194, Folder 7)
    - -Sculpture Exhibit, APR 1980 (Box 194, Folder 8)
    - -Unsworth Party (April 19, 1980) (Box 194, Folder 9)
  - -Bell, 1955 (Box 194, Folder 10)
  - -Bodman House, 1883-1996 (Box 194, Folder 11)
  - -Chapel Players-Godspell, 1989-1990 (Box 194, Folder 12)
  - -Counselors Committee, 1958-1962 (Box 194, Folder 13)
  - -Counselors Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 194, Folder 14)
  - -Counselors Committee, 1979-1980 (Box 194, Folder 15)
  - -Counselors Committee, 1981-1982 (Box 194, Folder 16)
  - -Counselors Committee, 1982-1983 (Box 194, Folder 17)
  - -Counselors Committee, 1984-1985 (Box 194, Folder 18)
  - -Counselors Committee-Board Membership/Chairship, 1983 (Box 194, Folder 19)
  - -Cross, 1967-1968 (Box 194, Folder 20)
  - -Dedication, 1955 (Box 194, Folder 21)
  - -Ecumenical Christian Church, 1978 (Box 194, Folder 22)
  - -Events
    - -General, 1959- (Box 194.1, Folder 1)
    - -General, undated (Box 194.1, Folder 2)
    - -Anniversaries
      [see (25th Anniversary)]
    - -Conway Celebration (April 17, 1985), 1984-1985 (Box 194.1, Folder 3)
    - -Inauguration of Mary Maples Dunn, 1985 (Box 194.1, Folder 4)
    - -Installation of John Betlyon (October 4, 1981) (Box 194.1, Folder 5)
    - -NECCA Symposium '88 (Box 194.1)
      [see 80. Religious Orgs-Newman Association]
  - -Funds
    - -Bodman Fund, 1955 (Box 194.1, Folder 6)
    - -Brooks Fund, 1962-1977 (Box 194.1, Folder 7)
    - -Chapel Library, 1976 (Box 194.1, Folder 8)
    - -James Foundation Grant, 1955-1956 (Box 194.1, Folder 9)
  - -Furnishings
    - -General, 1955-1956 (Box 194.1, Folder 10)
    - -Accoutrements, 1955-1959 (Box 194.1, Folder 11)
    - -Accoutrements-Catalogs, undated (Box 194.1, Folder 12)
    - -Accoutrements-Needlework, 1957-1963 (Box 194.1, Folder 13)
    - -Architectural Drawings of Ark of the Covenant, Hymn Board, and Sacristy
    - -Ark of the Covenant, 1956-1957 (Box 194.1, Folder 14)
    - -Artworks, 1955-1963 (Box 194.1, Folder 15)
    - -Artworks-Chagall Prints, 1956-1982 (Box 194.1, Folder 16)
    - -Correspondence-Hills, Helen Hills, 1958 (Box 194.1, Folder 17)
    - -Correspondence-Kane, Amanda, 1955-1957 (Box 194.1, Folder 18)
    - -Inventory, 1956 (Box 194.1, Folder 19)
  - -Groundbreaking, 1953-1954 (Box 194.1, Folder 20)
  - -Jewish Chaplaincy and Jewish Community, 1975-1985 (Box 194.1, Folder 21)
  - -Orders of Worship
    [see Individual Doca. Boxes, after Photos]
  - -Organ, 1956-1957 (Box 194.1, Folder 22)
  - -Plaques, undated (Box 194.1, Folder 23)
  - -Publications-Brochures, 1974- (Box 194.1, Folder 24)
  - -Publications-News From the Chapel, 1984-1988 (Box 194.1, Folder 25)
  - -Steeple, 1954 (Box 194.1, Folder 26)
  - -Weddings, 1955- (Box 194.1, Folder 27)
  - Chapel-Helen Hills Hills Chapel Record Book, 1955-1979 (194.3)
  - -Photographs
    - -Exterior, 1955- (Box 194.2, Folder 1)
    - -Interior, 1955- (Box 194.2, Folder 2)
    - -Groups and Individuals-Helen Hills Hills, 1953 (Box 194.2, Folder 3)
    - -Bell, undated (Box 194.2, Folder 4)
    - -Construction, 1954-1955 (Box 194.2, Folder 5)
    - -Steeple, undated (Box 194.2, Folder 6)
  - -Sketches and Drawings (Architectural), undated (Box 194.2, Folder 7)
  - -Orders of Worship-General, undated (Box 195, Folder 1)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1955-1956 (Box 195, Folder 2)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1956-1957 (Box 195, Folder 3)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1957-1958 (Box 195, Folder 4)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1958-1959 (Box 195, Folder 5)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1959-1960 (Box 195, Folder 6)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1960-1961 (Box 195, Folder 7)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1961-1962 (Box 195, Folder 8)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1962-1963 (Box 195, Folder 9)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1963-1964 (Box 195, Folder 10)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1964-1965 (Box 195, Folder 11)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1965-1966 (Box 195, Folder 12)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1966-1967 (Box 195, Folder 13)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1967-1968 (Box 195, Folder 14)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1969-1970 (Box 195, Folder 15)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1970-1971 (Box 195, Folder 16)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1971-1972 (Box 195, Folder 17)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1972-1973 (Box 195, Folder 18)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1973-1974 (Box 195, Folder 19)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1974-1975 (Box 195, Folder 20)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1975-1976 (Box 195, Folder 21)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1976-1977 (Box 195.1, Folder 1)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1977-1978 (Box 195.1, Folder 2)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1978-1979 (Box 195.1, Folder 3)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1979-1980 (Box 195.1, Folder 4)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1980-1981 (Box 195.1, Folder 5)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1981-1982 (Box 195.1, Folder 6)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1982-1983 (Box 195.1, Folder 7)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1984-1985 (Box 195.1, Folder 8)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1985-1986 (Box 195.1, Folder 9)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1994 (Box 195.1, Folder 9a)
  - -Orders of Worship, 1999 (Box 195.1, Folder 10)
  - -Orders of Worship, 2001 (Box 195.1, Folder 11)
  - -Orders of Worship-Thanksgiving Festival Service, 1971-1981 (Box 195.1, Folder 12)
- Chapel (Helen Hills Hills)- Funds, furnishings (Box 196)
  [RESTRICTED-75 years]
- Chapel (Helen Hills Hills)- Funds, Brooks Fund (Box 196.1)
  [RESTRICTED-100 years]
- Chapin House
  - -General, 1902-; undated (Box 197, Folder 1)
  - -Alumnae Reminiscences, 1989 (Box 197, Folder 2)
  - -Photographs-Exterior-Front View, 1904- (Box 197, Folder 3)
  - -Photographs-Exterior-Rear View, undated (Box 197, Folder 4)
  - -Photographs-Interior, 1904- (Box 197, Folder 5)
  - -Photographs-Groups, 1911- (Box 197, Folder 6)
- College Hall
  - -History-Lyman Estate, 1866 (Box 198, Folder 1)
  - -History by Esther Wyman 1911, 1966 (Box 198, Folder 2)
  - -Architecture, 1926- (Box 198, Folder 3)
  - -Architecture-Alumnae Association Office
  - -Architectural Report by Sarah Tiedeman 1949 (Box 198, Folder 4)
  - -Artifacts
  - -Carillon
    - -General, 1946- (Box 198, Folder 5)
    - -Clippings and Press Releases, 1919- (Box 198, Folder 6)
    - -Rededication, 1976 (Box 198, Folder 7)
    - -Miscellaneous, undated (Box 198, Folder 8)
  - -Chapel
    [see Chapel-College Hall Chapel]
  - -Clippings and Press Releases, 1874- (Box 198, Folder 9)
  - -Reading Rooms, undated (Box 198, Folder 10)
  - -Social Hall, 1890-1925; undated (Box 198, Folder 11)
  - -Windows- Elizabeth Seelye Bixler Memorial Window (Box 198, Folder 12)
  - -Photographs
    - -Exterior-Front View, 1875-1884 (Box 199, Folder 1)
    - -Exterior-Front View, 1885-1886 (Box 199, Folder 2)
    - -Exterior-Front View, 1887-1889 (Box 199, Folder 3)
    - -Exterior-Front View, 1890-1895 (Box 199, Folder 4)
    - -Exterior-Front View, 1896-1904 (Box 199, Folder 5)
    - -Exterior-Front View, 1905-1919 (Box 199, Folder 6)
    - -Exterior-Front View, 1920-1949 (Box 199, Folder 7)
    - -Exterior-Front View, 1950-1959 (Box 199, Folder 8)
    - -Exterior-Front View, 1960- (Box 199, Folder 9)
    - -Exterior-Front View, undated 1874-1952 (Box 200, Folder 1)
    - -Exterior-Front View, undated 1953- (Box 200, Folder 2)
    - -Exterior-Rear View, 1885-1887 (Box 200, Folder 3)
    - -Exterior-Rear View, 1888-1890 (Box 200, Folder 4)
    - -Exterior-Rear View, 1890- (Box 200, Folder 5)
    - -Exterior-Rear View, undated (Box 200, Folder 6)
    - -Exterior-Special Features, undated (Box 201, Folder 1)
    - -Exterior-Special Features-Clock Tower, 1948- (Box 201, Folder 2)